RG 004:015, Bridgeport Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Bridgeport Probate Court records
1790-1963
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Bridgeport District)
310 cubic feet
Probate record books, 1840-1955; Probate files, 1790-1963, bulk 1833-1963.
RG004_015
1916-001, 2011-005, 2011-031, T003013
Historical Note
Bridgeport, Fairfield County, Town established in May 1821, City incorporated May 1836, Parent Towns: Fairfield and Stratford
Bridgeport Probate District was constituted June 4, 1840, from the Stratford Probate District. At one time it also served the towns of Easton, March 5, 1878 - January 6, 1959; Huntington, now Shelton, June 1840 - May 1889; Monroe, June 1840 - January 6, 1859; and Trumbull, June 1840 - January 6, 1959. It currently serves the City of Bridgeport.
City of Bridgeport, Probate District chronology:
May 1821 - June 3, 1840, Stratford District
June 4, 1840 - Present, Bridgeport District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1840-1955. Contact the probate court for access to record books after Volume 193. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1790-1963. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1790-1940 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record Books:
The Bridgeport probate record books start with Volume 10. At the time the Bridgeport Probate District was created in 1840, the Stratford Probate District, of which it had been a part, was on Volume 10 of their record books. The Bridgeport Probate District began numbering with Volume 10.
From 1854 to 1860, the "Records and Orders" are included in the same volume.
The last volume to be titled "Records" is Volume 98. Beginning with Volume 99 the title became "Deceased Persons".
From 1860 to 1882, "Order Books" were numbered consecutively from Volume 12 through Volume 21, repeating volume numbers also used for "Records". These order books are listed after sequence of Volumes 10-193. From 1882 forward, "Order Books" are numbered within the same sequence as Records. Volume 33 is the first of these.
From 1870 to 1889, "Guardians, Conservators, etc." are in volumes lettered A, B, C, and D. These are listed after "Order Books", Volume 12-21. From 1889 forward, "Guardians, Conservators, etc." are numbered within the same sequence as "Records". Volume 48 is the first of these. Beginning in 1902 with Volume 105, the title of these volumes became "Minors, Incompetents, Insane, etc."
"Bonds" are in the same sequence as "Records", beginning in 1881 with Volume 30.
There is one volume of "Wills and Testaments" numbered Volume 1 that covers 1847-1866. This is listed after "Guardians, Conservators, etc.", Volume A-D.
The 3 index volumes are at the end.
Probate Files:
Accessions 1916-001 and T003013 are arranged alphabetically.
Accession 2011-031 is arranged first by starting letter of surname, then year, then alphabetically. For example, all of the A surnames are before all of the B surnames. Within the A surnames, all of the 1916 files are before the 1917 files. Within 1916 the files are alphabetical.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books are at the Bridgeport Probate Court.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in accession 1916-001 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-031.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Bridgeport; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Easton; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Huntington; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Monroe; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Shelton; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Trumbull
Places:
Bridgeport (Conn.); Easton (Conn.); Huntington (Conn.); Monroe (Conn.); Shelton (Conn.); Trumbull (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1976 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
All Bridgeport record books and files are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 11-162*, 1840-1916; probate files 1790-1940 (Accession 1916-001 only); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) have been microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
*The following volumes are not on microfilm: 14, 30, 36-37, 41, 43, 45, 47-48, 50, 52, 55-56, 58, 60, 62, 65, 67-68, 70, 72, 74, 76, 80-81, 84-87, 90-91, 94-96, 100-101, 104-107, 109, 111, 113, 115-116, 118-119, 121-122, 125-126, 128, 130-131, 133, 135, 137, 139, 141, 143, 145, 147-151, 153, 155, 157, 159, 161.
Provenance
The record books in accession 2011-005 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on July 26, 2010.
The probate files in accession 1916-001 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): March 22, 1916 (1836-1898); January 14, 1938 (1790, 1833-1915); February 3, 1941 (1851-1940). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
It is not known when the probate files in accession T003013 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library.
The probate files in accession 2011-031 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on September 16, 2010. The Bridgeport Probate Court is in the process of transferring all probate files to 1976 to the Connecticut State Library.
Container List
- Record books, 1840-1955; 103.5 cubic feet (208 volumes); 2011-005
  - Journal, 1840-1845 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1840-1844 (Volume 11)
  - Journal, 1846-1852 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1844-1851 (Volume 12)
  - Records and orders, 1851-1854 (Volume 13)
  - Records and orders, 1854-1865 (Volume 14)
  - Records and orders, 1857-1859 (Volume 15)
  - Records and orders, 1859-1860 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1859-1861 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1861-1863 (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1863-1864 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1865-1867 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1867-1869 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1869-1870 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1870-1872 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1872-1874 (Volume 24)
  - Journal, 1874-1876 (Volume 25)
  - Records, 1876-1878 (Volume 26)
  - Records, 1878-1879 (Volume 27)
  - Records, 1879-1880 (Volume 28)
  - Records, 1880-1881 (Volume 29)
  - Bonds, 1881-1888 (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1881-1883 (Volume 31)
  - Records, 1883-1884 (Volume 32)
  - Order book, 1883-1884 (Volume 33)
  - Records, 1884-1885 (Volume 34)
  - Records, 1885-1886 (Volume 35)
  - Order book, 1884-1886 (Volume 36)
  - Order book, 1886-1887 (Volume 37)
  - Records, 1886-1887 (Volume 38)
  - Order book, 1887 (Volume 39)
  - Records, 1887-1888 (Volume 40)
  - Order book, 1887-1888 (Volume 41)
  - Records, 1888 (Volume 42)
  - Order book, 1889 (Volume 43)
  - Records, 1889 (Volume 44)
  - Bonds, 1889-1894 (Volume 45)
  - Records, 1889-1890 (Volume 46)
  - Order book, 1889-1890 (Volume 47)
  - Guardians, Conservators, etc., 1889-1890 (Volume 48)
  - Records, 1890 (Volume 49)
  - Order book, 1890-1891 (Volume 50)
  - Records, 1890-1891 (Volume 51)
  - Order book, 1891-1892 (Volume 52)
  - Records, 1891-1892 (Volume 53)
  - Records, 1892 (Volume 54)
  - Order book, 1892 (Volume 55)
  - Guardians, conservators, etc., 1892-1894 (Volume 56)
  - Records, 1892 (Volume 57)
  - Order book, 1892-1893 (Volume 58)
  - Records, 1892-1893 (Volume 59)
  - Order book, 1893-1894 (Volume 60)
  - Records, 1893 (Volume 61)
  - Guardians, conservators, etc., 1894-1896 (Volume 62)
  - Records, 1893-1894 (Volume 63)
  - Order book, 1894 (Volume 64)
  - Records, 1894 (Volume 65)
  - Records, 1894-1895 (Volume 66)
  - Bonds, 1894-1899 (Volume 67)
  - Order book, 1894-1895 (Volume 68)
  - Records, 1895 (Volume 69)
  - Order book, 1895-1896 (Volume 70)
  - Records, 1895-1896 (Volume 71)
  - Guardians, conservators, etc., 1896-1898 (Volume 72)
  - Records, 1896 (Volume 73)
  - Order book, 1896-1897 (Volume 74)
  - Records, 1896-1897 (Volume 75)
  - Order book, 1897 (Volume 76)
  - Records, 1897 (Volume 77)
  - Records, 1897 (Volume 78)
  - Records, 1897-1898 (Volume 79)
  - Order book, 1897-1898 (Volume 80)
  - Conservators, guardians, etc., 1897-1899 (Volume 81)
  - Records, 1898 (Volume 82)
  - Records, 1898-1899 (Volume 83)
  - Order book, 1898-1899 (Volume 84)
  - Guardians, conservators, etc., 1899 (Volume 85)
  - Order book, 1899 (Volume 86)
  - Bonds, 1899 (Volume 87)
  - Records, 1899 (Volume 88)
  - Records, 1899-1900 (Volume 89)
  - Order book, 1900 (Volume 90)
  - Guardians, conservators, etc., 1899-1900 (Volume 91)
  - Records, 1900 (Volume 92)
  - Records, 1900-1901 (Volume 93)
  - Order book, 1900-1901 (Volume 94)
  - Guardians, conservators, etc., 1900-1901 (Volume 95)
  - Order book, 1901-1902 (Volume 96)
  - Records, 1901 (Volume 97)
  - Records, 1901 (Volume 98)
  - Deceased persons, 1901-1902 (Volume 99)
  - Order book, 1902 (Volume 100)
  - Guardians, conservators, etc., 1901-1902 (Volume 101)
  - Deceased persons, 1902-1903 (Volume 102)
  - Deceased persons, 1902-1903 (Volume 103)
  - Order book, 1903 (Volume 104)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1902-1903 (Volume 105)
  - Order book, 1897 (Volume 106)
  - Bonds, 1903-1906 (Volume 107)
  - Deceased persons, 1904 (Volume 108)
  - Records, 1904 (Volume 109)
  - Deceased persons, 1904 (Volume 110)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1904-1905 (Volume 111)
  - Deceased persons, 1905 (Volume 112)
  - Order book, 1905 (Volume 113)
  - Deceased persons, 1905 (Volume 114)
  - Order book, 1905-1906 (Volume 115)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1906-1907 (Volume 116)
  - Deceased persons, 1906 (Volume 117)
  - Order book, 1906 (Volume 118)
  - Bonds, 1906 (Volume 119)
  - Deceased persons, 1907 (Volume 120)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1907 (Volume 121)
  - Order book, 1907 (Volume 122)
  - Deceased persons, 1907 (Volume 123)
  - Deceased persons, 1907-1908 (Volume 124)
  - Order book, 1908 (Volume 125)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1908 (Volume 126)
  - Deceased persons, 1908 (Volume 127)
  - Order book, 1908 (Volume 128)
  - Deceased persons, 1909 (Volume 129)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1909 (Volume 130)
  - Bonds, 1909 (Volume 131)
  - Deceased persons, 1909 (Volume 132)
  - Order book, 1909 (Volume 133)
  - Deceased persons, 1910 (Volume 134)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1910 (Volume 135)
  - Deceased persons, 1910 (Volume 136)
  - Order book, 1910 (Volume 110)
  - Deceased persons, 1910-1911 (Volume 138)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1911 (Volume 139)
  - Deceased persons, 1911 (Volume 140)
  - Order book, 1911 (Volume 141)
  - Deceased persons, 1912 (Volume 142)
  - Order book, 1912 (Volume 143)
  - Deceased persons, 1912 (Volume 144)
  - Bonds, 1912 (Volume 145)
  - Deceased persons, 1913 (Volume 146)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1912 (Volume 147)
  - Order book, 1913 (Volume 148)
  - Bonds, 1915 (Volume 149)
  - Bonds, 1916 (Volume 150)
  - Order book, 1913 (Volume 110)
  - Deceased persons, 1913 (Volume 152)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1913 (Volume 153)
  - Deceased persons, 1914 (Volume 154)
  - Order book, 1914 (Volume 155)
  - Deceased persons, 1914 (Volume 156)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1914 (Volume 157)
  - Deceased persons, 1915 (Volume 158)
  - Order book, 1915 (Volume 159)
  - Deceased persons, 1915 (Volume 160)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1915 (Volume 161)
  - Deceased persons, 1915 (Volume 162)
  - Order book, 1915 (Volume 163)
  - Order book, 1916 (Volume 164)
  - Deceased persons, 1916 (Volume 165)
  - Order book, 1916 (Volume 166)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1916 (Volume 167)
  - Deceased persons, 1916 (Volume 168)
  - Deceased persons, 1917 (Volume 169)
  - Order book, 1917 (Volume 170)
  - Order book, 1918 (Volume 171)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1917 (Volume 172)
  - Deceased persons, 1917 (Volume 173)
  - Deceased persons, 1917 (Volume 174)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1918 (Volume 175)
  - Deceased persons, 1918 (Volume 176)
  - Order book, 1918 (Volume 177)
  - Bonds, 1918 (Volume 178)
  - Order book, 1919 (Volume 179)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1918 (Volume 180)
  - Deceased persons, 1918 (Volume 181)
  - Deceased persons, 1919 (Volume 182)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1983 (Volume 183)
  - Order book, 1919 (Volume 184)
  - Order book, 1920 (Volume 185)
  - Deceased persons, 1919 (Volume 186)
  - Deceased persons, 1919 (Volume 187)
  - Bonds, 1920 (Volume 188)
  - Deceased persons, 1920 (Volume 189)
  - Minors, incompetents, insane, etc., 1920 (Volume 190)
  - Order book, 1920-1921 (Volume 191)
  - Order book, 1921 (Volume 192)
  - Deceased persons, 1920 (Volume 193)
  - Order book, 1860-1863 (Volume 12)
  - Order book, 1863-1866 (Volume 13)
  - Order book, 1866-1870 (Volume 14)
  - Order book, 1870-1872 (Volume 15)
  - Order book, 1872-1874 (Volume 16)
  - Order book, 1874-1876 (Volume 17)
  - Order book, 1876-1877 (Volume 18)
  - Order book, 1878-1879 (Volume 19)
  - Order book, 1879-1881 (Volume 20)
  - Order book, 1881-1882 (Volume 21)
  - Guardians, conservators, etc., 1870-1878 (Volume A)
  - Guardians, conservators, etc., 1878-1883 (Volume B)
  - Guardians, conservators, etc., 1883-1886 (Volume C)
  - Guardians, conservators, etc., 1886-1889 (Volume D)
  - Wills and distributions, 1857-1866 (Volume 1)
  - Index, to 1899 (Volume 1)
  - Index, 1899-1913 (Volume 2)
  - Index, 1913-1926 (Volume 3)
  - Miscellaneous volumes
    - Abstract, Fairfield Probate Court to 1721
    - Adoptions, 1919-1936
    - Inventory of estate of George A. Wells, 1892
    - Record of certificates of election of town clerks and registrars of births, marriages, and deaths, 1879-1955
    - Settlement of estates, 1841-1856
- Probate Files, 1790-1940, bulk 1833-1898; 96 cubic feet; 1916-001
  - Probate files, 1790-1940, bulk 1833-1898 (Box 1-192)
    Arranged alphabetically.
- Inventory Control Book, 1790-1940; T003073
  Index of the two accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1916-001
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate Files, 1899-1915; 68.5 cubic feet; T003013
  - Probate files, 1899-1915 (Box 1-137)
    Arranged alphabetically
    There is no index for this accession
- Probate Files, 1916-1963; 42 cubic feet; 2011-031
  - Probate files, 1916-1963 (Box 1-42)
    The Connecticut State Library has 1916 Albrecht through 1955 Bobalki